NO BOY NO CRY ore zenshin GO
no boy, no cry, I advance go!
shounen yo kiite kure
hey boys, listen up
ningen nante taishita mon ja nai sa
humans aren't such a big deal
ashita nante moui ranai kara
who needs tomorrow anyway
nigitta kobushi wo kakusu na yo
so don't hide your fists
fuan ni yume wo
you're not old enough
uri tobasu hodo mada oiborechainai daro
to sell your dreams away to uncertainty
shounen yo kokoro no jyuu no
hey boys, you're the only ones
hikigane wo hikeru no wa kimi dake sa
who can pull the trigger in your heart
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids said
doushi yo mo naku kudaranai
we're living in this senseless, ridiculous,
kono subarashii sekai ni tattaima ikiteiru kara
awesome world right at this moment,
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids said
subete no hontou to uso wo
don't forget every truth or lie
kesshite wasurete shima wa nai you ni
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids said
shinu ni wa mosugiru darou
we're way too young to die
shiraketa tsura ga naranderu karappo no kono machi de
in this empty town lined with empty faces
subete no wakamono wa iitta
all the kids took off
kaze no nai kono yoru ni
into this windless night
nanika wo kaeyou to shiteru kara
because they want to change something
{The Showdown of
{Fate!
{You Can't Defeat Me
What incredible Chakra...
It's making my skin tingle.
My nose too...
Mizuki...
What's the matter?
Aren't you coming?
You jerk...!
Hey, Naruto!
Stop that!
You idiot.
Naruto!
Hey, hey.
Should you really be worrying
about others right now?
He's fast!
And what's more, such power...
So this is the power Orochimaru-sama
was talking about...
Amazing... It's almost scary...
Don't you agree, Iruka?
Mizuki, please stop.
Please...!
Tsubaki...
I don't care what happens
to me...
I just don't want you to
commit any more crimes.
Please!
Return to the village.
Tsubaki... If you care that much
about me,
then you could at least
be useful to me!
Tsubaki...!
What?!
You're so slow.
Iruka-sensei...!
Damn!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Hasty as always, huh...
You sure haven't made
any progress, have you?
He vanished!
He didn't vanish.
He's just fast.
That guy's been accelerating since earlier
and moving into our blind spots...
In that case...
Everybody, better be very aware
of your surroundings!
I call it
Uzumaki Whirlpool Formation!
— Right!
I see...
Even an idiot like him comes up
with an idea once in a while.
In that case...
I want to watch you experience
even deeper despair...
Despair that's equal to that wisdom
you've managed to muster!
There he is!
I see him!
It's not that you saw me.
I'm going out of my way
to show myself to you.
There!
Damn... Even though I can see him,
I'm unable to land any blows.
I'm telling you, I'm not foreseeing
your movements.
You're just sluggish.
Oww...
Hey, serves you right.
You demon fox.
Don't be so delighted in such
a big way.
You'll now get a taste of
the same agony I have endured.
Starting now, right, Naruto?
There's still much more
to come!
Stop that, Mizuki!
Don't lay your hands on Naruto!
Shut up, Iruka!
Do you have any idea how much
I've been waiting for this moment?
I've been waiting for this day
ever since then.
For this time of revenge.
I will use this power of mine
and take my own good time
to crush each of you, one at a time.
Come on, stand up, Iruka.
I'll start by killing this guy.
Mizuki...!
There you go.
That's good!
Come on!
You are pathetic.
There's a world of difference
between us, isn't there?
I've gotten my hands on
this extreme body
and it is your fate
to die wretchedly.
What do you mean,
"extreme body"?
When your power depends
on potions,
it's not true power!
That sounds just like
the half-baked guy you are...
In that case, go ahead
and try winning...
Using that real power
you're talking about!
I'm different from you.
You're gonna live out your life...
as some lowly teacher who never thinks
about getting ahead in life,
who only gets used by the village
in whatever way they see fit.
How do you like... this power...
and the way I carry myself?!
Even if you trained
a hundred years,
you'll never be able
to earn it!
I'm not gonna stop here!
I'm still gonna get much
much stronger...
I'll get Orochimaru to share
his Hidden Jutsu with me.
Do you really think that will happen?
I'm getting tired of you
playing the martyr.
I think it's about time
to end this.
Isn't this nostalgic...?
This time, I'll get you for sure.
So prepare yourself.
Naruto!
You jerk! Don't you dare lay
your hands on Iruka-sensei!
This is really something!
Every little thing is exactly the same
as it was that other time.
But I've changed.
The reason for my defeat
that time...
was that I let my guard down
to the demon fox that you are.
Wh-What's that?!
I won't let my guard down again.
I'll call upon all my strength
to beat you down!
Bring it on!
I'm sorry... both of you...
Choji!
Damn... If only I had a little more
information about those guys...
Elder Brother...
My body feels lighter.
Yeah, Raijin, it feels lighter,
doesn't it?
Okay, time for clobbering...
Yeah! Clobbering!
There they come.
Damn it!
Huh?
What the hell is this?!
M-My body...
Doesn't move...!
Huh? Genjutsu Paralysis?
Looks like I made it in time.
Good work!
Shikamaru, Ino, Choji!
Leave the rest to me!
The F-Fifth Hokage!
No way...
Hokage-sama... in person?!
Tsunade-sama.
I'm sorry I found out
about this so late.
But I wouldn't have imagined
that these guys were
hanging out with Mizuki...
Fifth Hokage!
We are saved...!
Uh... uh... Elder Brother...
Oh... Oh...
Well, we run into each other
in unusual places, don't we,
Fujin and Raijin?
T-Tsunade...
Let me ask what
you're doing here.
Powerful.
More like, scary.
Now then, is there something
you want to say?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Please forgive me.
We'll never do it again!
So you guys went with Mizuki
because he told you that
you'd be able to eat something good
at Orochimaru's place?
— I'm, I'm sorry.
No way we could stand up to guys on the
same level as the Three Legendary Ninja.
But I wonder what happened
between them the past...
to make those two that scared.
No thanks. I don't even want
to imagine what it might be.
Gimme a break.
Falling for such an obvious bait!
Mizuki has apparently gone
into those mountains up ahead.
Naruto and Iruka are probably
with him...
You guys come along
after recuperating a little.
Huh... wait a minute.
What are we going to do
with these two guys?
Huh? You don't need
to worry about that...
More importantly, I can't let them
cause any more trouble.
I've decided to make these guys
go home on their own.
Hey, Fujin, Raijin. I assume
you understand this already,
but if you're even one minute late
you're not getting any dinner.
— Yes, ma'am!
We can't be doing this, Raijin.
Let's hurry back to the institution.
Elder Brother, dinner, right?!
Dinner!
— Dinner, dinner, dinner, dinner...
Amazing...
what incredible speed.
It's very important for
a person to eat, after all.
That's just you.
Damn! His power is
even greater than earlier!
But I can't let him
take me down.
This guy may have a lead
to Sasuke's whereabouts.
Naruto!
Iruka, are you all right?
Yes...
Did you notice?
What?
Although that jerk's power
has increased multifold,
the sharpness of his movements
is diminishing.
Huh?
Did he transfer the Chakra
he was using for speed, to power?
I don't really know that, but...
That's quite a heavy burden
for Naruto to bear alone.
But if that guy's speed
has diminished,
there might be a chance to win.
All right... You hang in there
a little bit more, Naruto!
How about this,
you little brat?
Do you like the power of this body
that Orochimaru-sama gave me!
I'll tear you apart.
Where the hell is he...?
That Orochimaru...
Where is he?
Why would I tell a little brat
like you that kind of thing?
He wasn't in
the Village Hidden in the Sound.
The Village Hidden in the Sound?
Did you go there?!
The compound was
already totally empty...
Neither Sasuke nor Orochimaru
was there anymore.
You really gave that one
a lot of thought for a guy like you, huh...
I don't know where you heard that
about the Village Hidden in the Sound...
but if you're trying to fluster me
by talking rubbish like that,
it's not gonna happen.
Give up 'cause you're going
to the next world.
Listen carefully. Don't you dare talk
that kind of trash again!
Naruto, this way.
Iruka-sensei...
Just try to catch me!
You jerk... don't even think
I'm gonna let you get away!
Now! Jump up, Naruto!
All right!!
Damn... this is...!
Seal and Capture Perimeter!
The Capture and Arrest Jutsu!
Rasengan!
Naruto, that Jutsu is...
So that's the Fourth Hokage's
Jutsu... Rasengan...
Are you all right, Iruka-sensei?
Naruto, that was spectacular.
Good work!
Listen Sensei...
It looks like this guy didn't know
about the Village Hidden in the Sound.
So I was thinking that he's no longer...
with Orochimaru...
Don't talk trash...
Mizuki...
You gotta be kidding...
This is an extreme body that
I received from Orochimaru-sama...
I will go to the Village of Hidden Sound
and become even more...
Iruka-sensei, what's this?!
It's just as I thought, after all.
Grandma Tsunade...
Tsunade-sama.
His cells have started dying.
You jerk...
What have you done to me?!
It's not Naruto's fault.
It's caused from the substances
you took!
What? That's impossible!
You're getting a taste of
your own medicine.
That substance wasn't
fully developed yet.
The last casualty has been recovered.
It appears that Shizune was injured,
but there's no threat to her life.
I see. Thanks for your work.
That's a relief... Shizune is safe.
Orochimaru probably developed
that substance by chance
while he was trying to develop
a Forbidden Jutsu.
What is certain is that
that substance assimilates
the DNA of animals
and when it combines
with the human body
that serves to draw out its power
in an explosive manner.
But its effect is only short term.
And in exchange,
it puts a strain on the cells
that far exceeds the limits
of the human body.
It certainly isn't something
that's one could actually use.
But why did Mizuki...?
I don't know the details
but it must be that Mizuki
and Orochimaru
had a point of contact in the past...
However...
That tie has already been severed.
Yes, unfortunately Orochimaru
just used him as a plaything.
Giving him an unusable drug...
he's probably laughing his butt off.
But Mizuki is one lucky guy...
An ordinary Shinobi would
have lost his life.
Although he won't be able to live
his life as a Shinobi any more.
Unfortunate, isn't it, Naruto?
I kind of had that feeling anyway...
I see.
But I won't give up!
I will continue to do my best to search
for clues to Sasuke's whereabouts.
Tsubaki...
Damn it, Iruka!
Don't talk!
Next time I'll take you and that
little squirt down without fail.
There's no way you
could do that.
While you were pursuing
your futile dream,
Naruto's been actively honing
his skills.
You can't possibly catch up
with him any longer.
Mizuki can never go back
to being a Shinobi again...
Tsubaki...
I'm thinking of starting over
again too...
But first I must atone for
all the trouble I caused the village...
What a beautiful sunset.
Let's return to the village.
Dried and Canned Goods
Fish Market
I won't...
ever give up either!
I did it!
All right, since everybody
worked so hard today,
I'm going to do something special
and treat you all to a meal at Ichiraku.
Yippee! You're a real man,
Iruka-sensei!
I want a block of barbecued pork!
I want large portions of
all three kinds of ramen noodles —
miso, soy sauce and butter!
Hey, Iruka, before you do that,
you and Naruto need to go
to Leaf Village Hospital.
Huh... I told you I'm okay.
Don't argue with me.
Tsunade-sama!
I cleared the first stage!
She's just started her
ascetic training...
Could she be an exceptional talent
on par with Shizune...?
Hey, Sakura...!
This time you saved me...
You've really become stronger,
haven't you, Naruto.
kusottare na nyuusu ga toori sugite
crappy news pass us by
kimi wa kotoba wo nakusu
and you become speechless
boku no koe ja marude chiisa sugite
my voice is way too soft
kimi wa henji mo shinai
so you don't answer
kimi ga naiteru hitori de naiteru
you're crying, crying alone
boku wa dou suru boku mo naiteru no sa
what can I do? I'm crying too
yoru ni hitoribocchi no ore no sakebi ni nosete
"let my lonely scream ring out through the night"
zawameku jidai wo ore no supiido de buttobashiteku yeah yeah yeah yeah
I'll thrash this confused era with my speed, yeah
sanzameku yoru mo ore no supiido de buttobashiteku yeah yeah yeah yeah
and I'll thrash this confused night with my speed, yeah
tsunzaku gitaa to ore no supiido de buttobashiteku yeah yeah yeah yeah
I'll thrash them with my piercing guitar and my speed, yeah
katamuku sekai mo warui yatsura mo kechirashiteku yeah yeah yeah yeah
I'll take this sinking world, all its evil bastards, and kick their butts, yeah
I can't stand it any longer!
No matter how long I wait, there's no clue
about Sasuke's whereabouts!
And yet, Grandma Tsunade keeps
telling me not to do a thing!
At this rate, we'll never find Sasuke!
Isn't there anything?
Something, anything...
a clue to finding Sasuke!
Next time:
"Akamaru Gets Jealous of the Super Following Ability! Find the Illusionary Scent Bug."